

Computer Vision Researcher

NATIONALITY: Dutch | PRONOUNS: she/her/hers.

Roles: Researcher, adviser, lecturer, invited speaker, computer scientist.

Email: Silvia[dot]Laura[dot]Pintea[at]gmail[dot]com Webpage: http://silvialaurapintea.github.io

My work is in the field of AI, specifically Computer Vision and Deep Learning, where I have extensive experience with video and image analysis, specifically scale-invariance, video motion representations and regression problems.

My current focus is on effective video analysis and robust motion representations.

Work Experience

Senior PostDoc Division of Image Processing (LKEB), LUMC, Leiden, NL Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology (TUDelft), Delft, NL (Guest researcher) Job Description Efficient video and motion representations towards surgery video analysis. Period May 2022 — Present Researcher Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology (TUDelft), Delft, NL Job Description Focus on Deep Learning scale-invariance and efficiency. July 2020 — February 2022 Period Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology (TUDelft), Delft, NL PostDoc Collaboration with LUMC and the Geophysics department at TUDelft. Working on Job Description image and video analysis: geometric priors, scale-invariance, video representations, etc. July 2016 — July 2020 Period R&D Engineer Layar/Blippar, Amsterdam, NL

Job Description Efficient large-scale image matching and retrieval.

January — June 2016

EDUCATION

Period

PhD	Computer Vision, University of Amsterdam (UvA), Amsterdam, NL
Focus	Motion prediction, object localization, video representation learning
THESIS TITLE	Continuous Learning in Computer Vision
Period	2011 - 2015
\mathbf{MSc}	Artificial Intelligence, University of Amsterdam, (UvA) Amsterdam, NL
Focus	Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Neural Networks, Game Theory.
Period Avg. Grade	$2009 - 2011 \mid 8.31 \text{ (out of } 10)$
\mathbf{BSc}	Computer Science, University of Bucharest, Faculty of Mathematics and Computer
	Science, Bucharest, RO
Focus	Algorithms and data structures, Object oriented programming, Formal methods.
Period Avg. grade	2005 - 2008 9.40 (out of 10)

KEY PUBLICATIONS

- "A step towards understanding why classification helps regression" SL Pintea, Y. Lin, J. Dijkstra, JC van Gemert, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023.
- "Resolution learning in deep convolutional networks using scale-space theory", SL Pintea, N Tomen, SF Goes, M Loog, JC van Gemert, Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), 2021.
- "No frame left behind: Full Video Action Recognition", X Liu, SL Pintea, FK Nejadasl, O Booij, JC van Gemert. Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.
- "Déjà Vu: Motion Prediction in Static Images.", SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, AWM Smeulders, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2014.

Complete list of publications: https://scholar.google.nl/citations?user=shTkx9EAAAAJ&hl=en

QUALIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

BKO University teaching qualifications (TUDelft), completed in 2022.

PDP Tenure Track Personal Development Program (TUDelft), completed in 2021.

TEACHING AND GUIDING

COURSE RESPONSIBLE BSc Image Processing course (2021-2022), LECTURER BSc Image Processing course (2017-2022),

MSc Computer Vision course at TUDelft (2018-2022)

MSC ADVISER Tobias Stahl, Yichao Zhang, Chengqiu Zhang, Xilin Li, Yue Liu, Omar Hommos, Xi-

aoming Wen, Jian Zheng, Ziyu Bao, Yordan Dimitrov, Nikhil Saldanha, Ziyu Bao,

Jimmy Vlekke, Frans de Boer, Douwe Hoonhout

PHD ADVISER Xin Liu, Yancong Lin, Vedran Vukotic (visting student), Abolfazi Nadi (visiting stu-

dent)

PhD copromotor Yancong Lin, Xin Liu

Teaching Assistant BSc Short Course on Pattern Recognition (2017-2019)

COMMUNITY SERVICE & ADDITIONAL INFO

INVITED SPEAKER Startup Village (Amsterdam, 2022), AIRLab (Delft, 2019), NucTech meeting

(Delft, 2018), Delft-Leiden Deep Learning Seminars (Leiden, 2019)

INVITED LECTURER Deep Learning MSc course TUDelft (2019)

AWARD Outstanding Reviewer: CVPR (2021, 2022), ICCV (2021), ECCV (2022),

BMVC(2021, 2022)

Best paper award for the Workshop on Hands, ECCVw (2018)

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCES ICCV (2023,2021), CVPR (2021), ECCV (2020, 2016, 2014), ICIP (2018, 2016)

LOCAL CONFERENCES/EVENTS Video Understanding Symposium (2023), NCCV (2018 - 2023), NVPHBV

(2017), ICT.Open (2016, 2012)

REVIEWER (SINCE 2012) CVPR, ECCV/ICCV, BMVC, WACV, ICPR, TIP, IJCV PROGRAMMING Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, C/C++, Caffe, Torch, PHP,

Java, OpenCV, Dlib, Shogun, LibSVM, VlFeat, Yael, Matlab